Something beside
me. A light to the
[Music]
kerosene. And the places aren't real
anymore. And the faces don't say
[Music]
anything. In the silent
light of the mind blown
sphere. It's a
game. Devil's chess
club. Devil's chess club.
[Music]
Welcome to Devil's Chess Club. I'm Aaron
Good. This is the excerpted first
portion of the full episode of Devil's
Chess Club. If you want to see more of
the interview in today's episode, please
consider subscribing to the American
Exception podcast on Patreon. We have
hundreds of episodes available for
subscribers. If you want to better
understand subjects like the JFK
assassination and the role of organized
crime in our political regime, American
exception is the best place to go for
the deep history of the US empire. The
URL is
patreon.com/ameanexception. Subscribe if
you can and either way, please kindly
like this video and subscribe to this
American Exception channel.
John Keryaku, great to be with you. Hey,
great to be with you, Erin. Thanks for
having me. Yeah, it's great to have you
here again and uh here at the uh at the
precipice of doomsday uh it seems uh
perhaps. And I guess we can get right
into it. What do you make of this latest
attack on Russia's strategic air bombers
um which were kept in the open not under
hangers to be observable as Russia sort
of I mean they seem to be essentially
trying to adhere to the remnants of the
treaties the the former you know the the
treaties that people have withdrawn from
including Russia but were you know this
was still a reasonable measure to take
to try to adhere to these things so that
both sides know that there's not a first
strike coming. You know, you can look at
the other side's
bombers. What kind what what do you make
of the seriousness of this and the the
motivations and who who knew what in the
US?
Yeah. Wow. What an operation, huh? So,
I'm I'm of several opinions here. Uh
number one, I agree with you. I think
that the reason these things weren't
hanged was twofold. one because the
Russians, for whatever reason, decided
to allow them to be observable to
American satellites so that the
Americans could rest assured that they
were not in the process of being used,
there is no doomsday, that's that's
imminent and even though the the treaty
is not really in effect
anymore, they're still adhering to it.
So I agree with you. Number one, the
Russians were trying to do the right
thing on that issue. Number two, I think
there was a little bit of arrogance
involved here where these bombers for
the most part were so far away from
Ukraine that there was no chance, there
was no possibility that the Ukrainians
could hit them from Ukraine. And it
never occurred to the Russians that the
Ukrainians would have instituted this
operation to allow them to essentially
infiltrate Russia over the last 18
months and preposition drones, smuggle
in and pre-position drones to take the
bombers out.
Third, this was a colossal [__] on the
part of the Russians in
that the Ukrainians were able
to put these suicide
drones
into shipping
containers, smuggle them into Russia
over the last 18 months, prepositioned
them across Russia as far east as
Vlatavastto.
It doesn't get any farther east than
that. Russia has 11 time zones. This is
the
11th and then just patiently wait for
the moment when you want to launch this
operation. The media are telling us that
the Russians lost $2
billion worth of bombers in this
operation. Two billion dollars. It wiped
out their bombers.
And the fourth point is I think the
Russians probably should have seen
something like this coming even if they
had missed the fact that these drones
were smuggled in because this is what
every country that is at war does on the
eve of peace talks. You ratchet up the
attacks. you ratchet up the violence
hoping you can get another meter of
territory so that you can negotiate it
away at the uh at the peace talks. Like
what did the Russians think the
Ukrainians were going to do? Just throw
up their
hands? So yeah, I I was I was asked to
give a an interview to a Russian network
uh a few days ago and I did. I I
generally say to say yes to everybody
except the Lindon LaRouche people. And
um and they asked me, "Well, was this a
criminal act?" And I said,
"No, it was first of all, you're at war
and so it's not a criminal act to to
bomb a military target." Uh but it was a
brilliant act of espionage.
Brilliant. Some Ukrainian's going to get
a medal for this. It was
incredible.
gutsy and incredible in its result. Do
you think it will have the effect that I
mean you you're you would put this as a
um gambit to attempt to have more
leverage to show perhaps the Russ the
Russians that we can inflict more pain
on you if you don't come to the
negotiations. You know, we're not
totally just, you know, dead in the
water here. But I'm wondering if it's
really going to have that effect at all.
Because to me, what it really shows is
that it it affirms that having a NATO
uh outpost on your doorstep is totally
unacceptable. And to me, I think it will
just strengthen Russian resolve and
actually denazify Ukraine. And there and
that's exactly what it's done. That's
exactly what it's done. I'm sorry to
interrupt you. the the Russians released
their their demands uh for the for the
Turkey peace talks uh yesterday I think
it was and it's exactly the same set of
demands that they had in the very
beginning of the conflict they haven't
budged one inch not one iota they they
want uh the Donbass Keran Crimea uh
permanent uh military neutrality for
Ukraine and denazification this is exact
exactly what they said they wanted at
the very very start of this military
campaign. So, you're right, it didn't
have the effects that the Ukrainians, I
think, wanted it to have. And another
thing, too, I think that this
attack was just as much a message to
Donald Trump saying, "You can bloate all
you want about ending this war. we're
going to keep fighting and if you're not
going to help us, well, we're going to
rely on the Europeans and we're just
going to keep fighting
ourselves. And I think that's where they
left it,
right? I mean, it's just a
strange military conflict. I don't know
if there's one like it in history where
one side is so
overmatched and the the bigger picture
terms are all so unfavorable to it, you
know, with and so a tactical I I don't
even know the analogy here. It's like if
I hid behind a cleverly like, you know,
put myself under a box, you know, and
like walked around with it like in that
video game Metal Gear, right? And like I
I popped out of the box and I punched
Mike Tyson in the testicles, right? And
I'm like, "Yes, that was tactically
brilliant." And he's going to be like,
"Ah, you know, he's he might be hurt for
a minute or two, but then where am I
now?" Now I've got a very angry person
that I cannot hope to defeat, and I've
just provoked him in a really terrible
way. I mean, I I think that it's a
tactical success, but a very dumb one.
Strategic failure. You know, it that's a
really good analogy, too. And and one of
the things that I think did not play in
the Ukrainian
calculation
was that the Russians have access to
virtually unlimited ground troops, not
Russians and artillery and artillery
because they've got the North Koreans,
they have the Bella Russians, there are
reports of Chinese that have signed up
to fight. Um, I read yesterday that the
Ukrainians have lost something like
31,000
uh troops in combat. The Russians
perhaps double that. But Russia is
far larger and more populous than
Ukraine is. And they have these North
Koreans and Chinese and Bellar Russians
and whoever else wants to join the
Russian military. So this is not
something that the Ukrainians can keep
up forever. And you're right. I mean,
maybe they maybe they just stirred up a
hornets's nest, but I I think that they
are
hoping that Donald Trump has
some sway over Vladimir Putin. I don't
think he does, but I think they think
they hope he does and they can come out
with something that might look halfway
honorable uh in Turkey,
right? And I am really I'm I'm skeptical
of that. It doesn't seem that they can
they can do this. And the question is
what was the US knowledge of this?
because I feel that there's a there's
part of the US that would think okay we
want to have even though we know that we
are messing with Russia's deterrent
capability and that this could be
perceived as very threatening we want to
somehow have a way to inflict pain on
them to maybe get a better deal at the
end but there if if things don't work
there I mean I think that there is
potentially a a segment of the western
regime, the deep state, you know, the
the west western imperialism, US
imperialism that is so it cannot accept
the US being anything but the global
hegeimon. And since they they've lost
every way, the only thing that they
still have in their bag is a is a
nuclear war. And so maybe they're
thinking we will weaken Russia's ability
to wage nuclear war so that we can win a
nuclear war soon. I mean, these people
are such lunatics that I I mean, what do
you think are the chances that people
want this, want a nuclear? Well, I I I
think there are people who want that. I
think you're exactly right. There is a
faction, not just in Ukraine, but here
in the United States as well, that
believes a nuclear war is a winnable
war. that sure millions of people are
going to be wiped out, but like Pat
Buchanan said in 19 whatever it was,
1992 when he was running for president,
um, of course a nuclear war is winnable.
We come out from from our caves and we
pick up and continue the fight. And so I
think that there is a faction I know
it's crazy, right? I know that there is
a faction in Ukraine that believes that
a nuclear war is winnable or that even
if the the Russians were to resort to
nuclear
war, the Americans, the British, and the
French, also nuclear powers, will step
up against the Russians and
perhaps use nukes as well. And that's
insanity, of course, but I think that
that's probably a Ukrainian calculation.
that what what what would be the lesser
of two evils? To just let the Russians
roll into Europe, as people say, roll
into Europe, or or to use nuclear
weapons to preserve freedom and
democracy.
As far as rolling into Europe goes, why
you understand why Germany would want
the lean ramen? They were very explicit
about it. They needed Russian resources
to fuel a German industrial base and a
German war machine. There was a logic
behind exterminating the Slavs and
taking it for Leven's realm. An insane
evil Nazi logic, but a logic. Mhm. What
What is Reab have that Russia would need
to, you know, that would that would make
them invade Germany, for example? I
mean, honestly, I think the Europeans
need the Russians a lot more than the
Russians need the Europeans. When I was
in the UK just a few weeks ago, I was
giving a speech in Nottingham in in the
Royal Albert Hall, gorgeous historic uh
place, big round
uh event center. It was so freezing cold
in there that literally everybody was
complaining. And finally, the manager
told us, "We're just not getting Russian
gas and we can't afford to heat the
place. That's it." And that's that's
most of the most of the homes in the UK
and Germany and Greece. I was in Greece
this winter and it was freezing
everywhere you went because they're not
getting Russian gas anymore and it's
just too expensive to buy it from, you
know, the United States or or elsewhere.
So yeah, I I've come to the conclusion
that that the Russians don't need Europe
anywhere near how Europe needs Russia.
Ditto for China with the rare earth
metals. Uh oh yeah, this whole I don't
know why they sell us rare earth medals.
No, I don't either. I don't understand
why they do a number of things that they
do. They still send students to American
universities
um which and and high schools, you know,
private schools and so on. I'm wondering
how long that will be the case. And I
the US is really shooting itself in the
foot by not relying on its status as a
place where people even in adversarial
countries like China they still think
that we have something to offer in terms
of education. And I think that there are
good educational traditions in and
institutions in the US if you have money
especially
uh but and that they are working on
building their own but we're in this is
just another area where we're forcing
them to build their own. It's sort of
like a different version of import
substitute industrialization except it's
with like education and sending your
kids overseas but they don't need to do
that. They could hire, in fact, they
could probably hire a lot of Americans,
and they probably are, to teach in
Americanstyle schools. I do understand
that that's happening over in China. And
a lot of Americans would be happy to get
out of this country, which whose fascism
is now bubbling to the surface. It's not
even hidden anymore. And think of it
this way, too.
If I were the CIA
director, I would want as many Chinese
PhD students in American universities as
possible because every single one of
those Chinese PhD students should be a
CIA target for
recruitment. They're they're almost
exclusively in the hard
sciences, right? And they're going to go
back to China and they're going to take
positions of authority. they're going to
rise up through the ranks of, you know,
the Ministry of Defense or
whatever. I would want to recruit them
while they're in college in the United
States and then send them back to China
and and have them work in place. Number
one. Number two, you're exactly right
that the Chinese don't need us anywhere
near the way we need the Chinese. I'm
not talking about the US buying their
trinkets and their cheap junk that they
make and and send to the United States.
It's better these days though. Their
stuff is better. It's like it's like
Japan. Japan was known the same way.
They were the Japan was the producer of
cheap junk until suddenly by by becoming
good at that. They're actually I mean
they're going to make they're working on
semiconductors and such now. Yeah, they
are. That that is true. I'm thinking of
the bolt cutter that I bought at Home
Depot. Oh, yeah. that when I went to cut
a a Yale lock, the bolt cutter just like
exploded into five different pieces.
Anyway, um I I went to Hong Kong last
year for a conference. And I was struck
at how few places took Mastercard and
Visa, but they took this thing called
the Panda Card. And finally, I asked,
"What is this Panda card?" And they
said, "Oh, it's our national credit
card. It's like it's like Visa and
Mastercard." I said, "Why don't you just
use Visa Mastercard?" Oh, that's smarter
to use that. Yeah. Oh, much smarter
because they said Visa and Mastercard,
every transaction goes through New York.
Panda card, every transaction goes
through Shanghai. And so then we're not
subject to American sanctions. You know
what? I bet it's I bet it's I bet it's
nationalized, too. Oh, it is. I'm sure
it is. That's what I'm saying. We It's
brilliant. Yeah. No, we are idiots for
using Ma It's not just that they
shouldn't use Visa and Mastercard. We
should have some sort of nationalized
system because there's a couple bucks on
every transaction and it just goes to
the stockholders of Visa and Mastercard.
It's just it's rent seeking. It's the
same with it's the same everywhere.
That's a great point. It's why we're
going to lose to China because our
economy is so overpriced because we have
all these toll booths up and all these
little mafia rackets that are like, "Oh,
you want you want to pay for gas? We got
to get a little taste. Like everything
is about you're getting screwed every
way. That's all the capitalism has
become is a series of rackets and we're
not going to be able to compete with
them. They're going to have a better
society, better technology, happier
people and we're just stuck here as
neofudal, you know, rent peeons. That's
right. You're absolutely right. And why
is it that we see it and the people in
the White House and the Department of
the Treasury, regardless of who happens
to be president at any given time? Why
don't they see it? Because of the who
pays their campaigns. It's not they
don't get they don't campaign on the
basis of the public interest. They
campaign on pleasing people with money.
And the people that have money are the
people that own rackets that allow them
to just make money in their sleep and
bribe politicians. And that's right.
That's and that really is the West. But
you know this this issue of uh how this
is going to to change and how it is
changing uh is going to be the defining
issue of our time unless it's nuclear
war which I I hope isn't the case but do
you think that this settlement they're
having these talks let's getting back to
Russia here for a second they're having
these talks in Istanbul I think most
people are thinking they will not be
fruitful uh right and then potentially I
don't know if they when exactly they are
going to end if they have ended uh is
right now. I mean, I'm not even I I
should have checked this morning. I'm
more up to I checked this morning and
and they were still ongoing when you and
I started recording this, they were
ongoing. Yeah. But after this ends, I it
seems that we may be nearing the the
getting closer to the collapse of the
Ukrainian military. Everything that you
see about them impressing people off the
streets, you know, with these gangs
going around trying to get like these
hless people, you know, they're not
getting any good sort of training.
They're probably being, you know, I
don't know if it's to the state of like
the Russians at Stalingrad where they
give the rifles to the people in front
and they expect them to die. So then you
pick up the the dead guy's rifle, but
like it looks really bad for Ukraine.
What sort of settlement do you think
that we would end up seeing here? Do you
think that Russia would essentially cut
take all the Black Sea, Odessa, you
know, all the areas that are, you know,
I I don't think so. I think that in the
end the Russians are going to get
everything that they're demanding.
They're going to get the Donbass.
They're going to get Crimea. They're
going to have to be
recognized, at least de
facto. Uh they're going to get an
assurance that Ukraine will never be a
member of NATO. And the only concession
I could see them making is that they
would they would acquies
to Ukrainian membership in the European
Union, which they've already said. They
weren't opposing anyway. No, they
weren't they were never opposing that.
Um it's it it makes it better for
Russia. Yeah. So I I think it's bad for
the EU. The EU would have Yeah. It's not
good for the EU. It's an economic basket
case. It's one of the most corrupt
countries in the world and they're going
to have to subsidize it probably for the
next two decades. Wouldn't they be
obligated to take refuge you mean
migrants and such? Oh yes, without any
doubt. Yes. I'll tell you I go to I go
to um Iceland a lot on business. I go
every month or so and
um I've seen more Ukrainians in Iceland
than any other nationality. almost as
many Ukrainians as Icelanders that I've
dealt with. They work in every hotel.
They work in every restaurant and bar.
They work as cab drivers. The place is
absolutely full of Ukrainians. And none
of them have any plans to go back. They
like it just the way things are. Well,
John, I know that you have to go uh
because you have another interview. So,
um I just wanted to thank you again for
being here. Where can people follow your
work? Oh, thank you. Oh, thanks, Erin.
Um, there are a couple of things, more
than a couple. I've got uh two podcasts.
One is called Deep Focus with John
Kuryaku. That's on YouTube. I have a
podcast with Ted RAW called Deeprogram.
That's also on YouTube. I've got a TV
show on an online platform called
Unified TV, NU FYD. That show is called
CIA Declassified, where we take
declassified documents and tell the
historic, you know, background stories.
And um and I'm on Substack. Everything I
write, everything I
I appear in like this show here goes
right on Substack.
johnyaku.substack.com. And thank you so
much for having me. Yeah, very good. And
until next time, John. Thanks a lot.
Thank you.
Thanks to Dana Chavaria for producing
this episode and thank you for tuning
in.
Please do consider subscribing to the
American Exception podcast on Patreon.
The URL is
patreon.com/ameanexception. We need
subscribers because we will never be
viable on this platform. Isn't it
strange that the majority of alternative
media people who focus on the
clandestine crimes of the imperial
capitalist US regime? Isn't it strange
that the majority of these people are
political rightists? Shouldn't it be the
left that says, "Yeah, these greedy
criminals will do anything for money and
power." Somehow many on the left think
it is a mark of sophistication to deny
state crimes like the assassinations of
JFK, RFK, Martin Luther King, and
Malcolm X. I have to believe that a lot
of algorithmic juice and social
engineering has gone into keeping the
left studiously ignorant about the
institutionalized criminality of our
system of governance. We need to fight
against this. So again, please do
consider subscribing to the American
Exception podcast on Patreon. The URL is
patreon.com/ameanexception. Subscribe so
that we can keep bringing light to the
devil's chessboard.